Here comes the mother f*%#ing bride!
The Bride! is a science fiction, horror, comedy
film directed by Maggie Gyllenhaal.
A lonely Frankenstein travels to 1930s Chicago to
ask groundbreaking scientist Dr.
Euphronious to create a companion for him.
The two revive a murdered young woman and The Bride is born.
But what ensues is beyond what either of them imagined.
The Bride, played by Jessie Buckley.
Frankenstein's Monster, played by Christian Bale.
Dr. Euphronious, played by Annette Bening.
Myrna, played by Penélope Cruz.
is an upcoming American gothic crime film written,
co-produced, and directed by Maggie Gyllenhaal.
The film stars Jessie Buckley, Christian Bale, Peter Sarsgaard,
Annette Bening, Jake Gyllenhaal, and Penélope Cruz.
The film draws inspiration from the 1935 film Bride of Frankenstein directed by James Whale, itself
inspired by the 1818 novel Frankenstein; or, The Modern Prometheus by Mary Shelley.
is scheduled to be released in the United States by Warner Bros.
Pictures on March 6, 2026.
The film explores themes of chicago, illinois, murder, back
from the dead, companion, woman director.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and thought_provoking.